Guide to the United States Power Squadrons District 16 records 1939-2020
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
- Publications and Newsletters, 1958-2012; Series VIII.
  - Bell Signals, 2012 (Box-folder 12/15)
  - The Pilot (Seattle Sail and Power Squadron Newsletter), July-October, 2001 (Box-folder 12/16)
  - The Pike Pole (Everett Sail and Power Squadron Newsletter), September-November, 2001 (Box-folder 12/17)
  - Currents (U.S. Power Squadron Educational Department Newsletter), January, May, September, 2002 (Box-folder 12/18)
  - The Ensign Magazine (The Official Magazine of the U.S. Power Squadron), January-December, 2003 (Box-folder 12A/1)
  - The Ensign Magazine, January-December, 2004 (Box-folder 12A/2)
  - The Ensign Magazine, January-August, 2005 (Box-folder 12A/3)
  - The Ensign Magazine, December 2005-December 2006 (Box-folder 12A/4)
  - The Ensign Magazine, January-December 2007 (Box-folder 12A/5)
  - The Ensign Magazine, January-December 2008 (Box-folder 12A/6)
  - The Ensign Magazine, January 2009- Winter 2010 (Box-folder 12A/7)
  - Cardinal Points (USPS District 16 Newsletter) (Bound Volume), Volumes 5-17, 1958-1971 (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Cardinal Points (Bound Volume), Volumes 18-22, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Cardinal Points (Notebook), Volumes 23-63, 1976-1998 (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Cardinal Points (Duplicates), Volumes 5-17, 1958-1971 (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Cardinal Points (Duplicates), Volumes 18-22, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Cardinal Points, 1980-1998 (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Cardinal Points, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Cardinal Points, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 13/8)
  - Cardinal Points, 2003-2010 (Box-folder 13/9)
- Membership Information, 1941-2009; Series IX.
  - District 16 Rosters (Incomplete) (Bound Volume), 1948-1977 (Box-folder 14/1)
  - District 16 Rosters (Bound Volume), 1970, 1977-1987 (Box-folder 14/2)
  - District 16 Rosters, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 14/3)
  - District 16 Rosters, 1994-2004 (Box-folder 14/4)
  - District 16 Rosters, 2005-2010 (Box-folder 14/5)
  - District 16 Membership Info, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 14/6)
  - USPS National Directory of Officers, 1974-1985 (Incomplete) (Box-folder 14/7)
  - USPS National Directory of Officers, 1986-1992 (Incomplete) (Box-folder 14/8)
  - USPS National Directory of Officers, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 14/9)
  - USPS National Directory of Officers, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 14/10)
  - USPS Fleet/Membership Rosters, 1954 (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Seattle Sail and Power Squadron Roster, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 15/2)
  - USPS Bulletin, 1941 (Box-folder 15/3)
  - USPS Approved Auxiliaries Directory, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Canadian Power Squadron, Pacific Mainland District Rosters, 1967-1996 (Incomplete) (Box-folder 15/5)
  - Canadian Power Squadron, Vancouver Island District Rosters, 1991, 1996 (Box-folder 15/6)
  - 13th Coast Guard District Auxiliary Directory, 1995 (Box-folder 15/7)
- Bellingham Power Squadron Files, 1958-2017; Series X.
  - Pennant Plans, 1961 (Box-folder 15/8)
  - Bylaws, 1958-1995 (Box-folder 15/9)
  - Conference Fund, 1994 (Box-folder 15/10)
  - History, 1958-1988 (Box-folder 15/11)
  - Fall Conference in Bellingham, 1974 (Box-folder 15/12)
  - Bellingham Squadron Change of Watch, 1998 (Box-folder 15/13)
  - Administrative Files, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 15/14)
  - Administrative Files, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 15/15)
  - Administrative Files, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 15/16)
  - Administrative Files, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 15/17)
  - Administrative Files, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 15/18)
  - Administrative Files, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 15/19)
  - Administrative Files, 1968 (Box-folder 15/20)
  - Administrative Files, 1969 (Box-folder 15/21)
  - Administrative Files, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 15/22)
  - Administrative Files, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 15/23)
  - Administrative Files, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 15/24)
  - Administrative Files, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 15/25)
  - Administrative Files, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 15/26)
  - Administrative Files, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 15/27)
  - Administrative Files, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 15/28)
  - Administrative Files, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 15/29)
  - Administrative Files, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 15/30)
  - Administrative Files, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 15/31)
  - Administrative Files, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 16/1)
  - Administrative Files, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 16/2)
  - Administrative Files, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 16/3)
  - Administrative Files, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 16/4)
  - Administrative Files, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 16/5)
  - Administrative Files, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 16/6)
  - Administrative Files, 1997 (Box-folder 16/7)
  - 25th Anniversary Files, 1984 (Box-folder 16/8)
  - 25th Anniversary Guest Book, 1984 (Box-folder 16/9)
  - Administrative Files, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 16/10)
  - Handouts and Notices, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 16/11)
  - Announcements and Flyers (Change of Watch Meetings), 2002 (Box-folder 16/12)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Officers, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 16/13)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Fall Conference Invite, 1960 (Box-folder 16/14)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Membership Roster, 1960-1985 (Box-folder 16/15)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Membership Rosters, 1985-1998 (Box-folder 16/16)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Membership Rosters, 1998-2009 (Box-folder 16/17)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Membership Rosters, 2009-2012 (Box-folder 16/18)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, 2009 (Box-folder 16/19)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, 2010 (Box-folder 16/20)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, 2011 (Box-folder 16/21)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, January-March 2012 (Box-folder 16/22)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, April 2012 (Box-folder 16/23)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, May 2012 (Box-folder 16/24)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, June-July 2012 (Box-folder 16/25)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, August 2012 (Box-folder 16/26)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, September 2012 (Box-folder 16/27)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, October 2012 (Box-folder 16/28)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, November 2012 (Box-folder 16/29)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, December 2012 (Box-folder 16/30)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, January 2013 (Box-folder 16/31)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, February 2013 (Box-folder 16/32)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Squadron Archives, March 2013 (Box-folder 16/33)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, October 2015 (Box-folder 16B/1)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, November 2015 (Box-folder 16B/2)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, December 2015 (Box-folder 16B/3)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, January 2016 (Box-folder 16B/4)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, February 2016 (Box-folder 16B/5)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, March 2016 (Box-folder 16B/5)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, March 2016 (Box-folder 16B/6)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, April 2016 (Box-folder 16B/7)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, May 2016 (Box-folder 16B/8)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, June 2016 (Box-folder 16B/9)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, July/August 2016 (Box-folder 16B/10)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, September 2016 (Box-folder 16B/11)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, October 2016 (Box-folder 16B/12)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, November 2016 (Box-folder 16B/13)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, December 2016 (Box-folder 16B/14)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, January 2017 (Box-folder 16B/15)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, February 2017 (Box-folder 16B/16)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Archives, March 2017 (Box-folder 16B/17)
- Agate Pass Records, 1953-2020; Series XI.
  - Roster, 1963-1964 (Box-folder AP_01/1)
  - Newsletters: The Halyard, 1991 (Box-folder AP_01/2)
  - Photographs, approximately 1991-1995 (Box-folder AP_01/3)
  - Photographs, approximately 1960s (Box-folder AP_01/4)
  - Photographs, approixmately 1990-2004 (Box-folder AP_01/5)
  - Clippings and printouts, approximately 1990s-2004 (Box-folder AP_01/6)
  - Flags, undated (Box-folder AP_01/7)
  - Scrapbooks, 1953-1968 (Box AP_02)
  - 2018 District 16 Rendezvous
    Electronic resources - contact repository re: access to digital files.
  - Agate Pass Rosters, 2020
  - DR Buoy Painting, 2018
  - Port Ludlow Marker, undated
  - Pot Soup Rendezvous, 2019
  - Squadron History, approximately 2018-2019
  - Xmas December Meeting, undated
  - Xmas Parade, 2019
- Photographs, 1945-1995; Series XII.
  - Photo Album, District 16 Spring Council, District 16 Spring Conference, Spring Governing Board Meeting, District 16 Rendezvous, Fall Governing Board, District 16 Fall Council, Fall Conference, 1985 (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Photo Album, USPS Annual Meeting, Fall Council, District 32 Spring Conference, Spring Conference, Spring Governing Board, District Rendezvous, Fall Council Meeting, Fall Governing Board, Fall Conference, Annual Meeting, 1986 (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Photo Album, District 16 Spring Conference, Educational Seminar, 1988 General Meeting, Governing Board Meeting, National Rendezvous, USPS 75th Anniversary, 1989 District 16 Rendezvous, 1989 Fall Conference, 1990 Spring Conference, 1990 District 16 Rendezvous, 1990 Fall Conference, 1987 (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Photo Album, Voyage of the Ensign - Governor Booth Gardner being “Pinned”, Bremerton/Agate Pass, Spokane, Poverty Bay/Tacoma/Olympia, Seattle/Possession Sound/Everett, Port Angeles, Deception Pass with race, Bellevue Rendezvous, Friday Harbor with Cruise, Pole Pass, Bellingham/Transfer of Ensign to PMDe, 1989 (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Photo Album, Undated (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Photo Album, 1984 (Box-folder 18/2)
  - Photo Album, 1945-1955 (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Photo Album, 1945-1955 (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Photo Album, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Photo Album, 1950-1960 (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Photo Album (Commander’s Photo Album), 1946-1988 (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Photo Album, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Photo Album, 1984 (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Photo Album, 1991 (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Photo Album, 1993 (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Photo Album, 1994 (Box-folder 20/4)
  - Photo Album, 1995 (Box-folder 21/1)
  - Photo Album, 1995 (Box-folder 21/2)
  - Photo Album, 1957 (Box-folder 21/3)
- Awards and Memorabilia, 1946-1990; Series XII.
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Full Certificate Members Plaque, 1973-1990 (Box-folder 22/1)
  - Squalicum Yacht Club Darwin Personius Award, 1996 (Box-folder 22/2)
  - Awards/Certificates, 1959-1996 (Box-folder 22/3)
  - Bellingham Squadron “Shipping Over” Plaque, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 22/4)
  - Merit Mark Award (Photocopy) Awarded to Herb Hearsey, 1997 (Box-folder 22/5)
  - Merit Mark Award Awarded to Herb Hearsey, 2000 (Box-folder 22/6)
  - Pamphlets and Handouts, 1967-1985 (Box-folder 22/7)
  - District 16 Buttons, 1954-1994 (Box-folder 22/8)
  - District 16 Bookmark, Undated (Box-folder 22/9)
  - Photo (from exhibit – Bob Bourbon), 1946 (Box-folder 22/10)
  - Membership Registry, 1960-72 (Box-folder 22/11)
  - Excellence in Recreational Boating Education, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 22/12)
  - Educational Fund Certificate of Merit, 2008 (Box-folder 22/13)
  - Annual Teaching Aids Exhibit and Competition 2nd Place, 2002 (Box-folder 22/14)
  - Excellence in Recreational Boating Education, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 22/15)
- Oversized Materials, 1939-1970; Series XIV.
  - Photograph of annual midwinter dinner and dance, 1946 (Oversize-box OV/1)
  - Display board re: Squadron history etc, Undated (Oversize-box OV/2)
  - Tacoma power squadron – certificate (First Squadron charter in Pacific NW), 1939 (Oversize-box OV/3)
  - Copy, second charter (Seattle Power Squadron), 1941 (Oversize-box OV/4)
  - Display Board with District 16 Conference Pamphlets, 1959-1979 (Oversize-box OV/5)
  - Boating Classes poster, 1970 (Oversize-box OV/6)
  - Local Squadron Charter, 1959 (Oversize-box OV/7)